Where... am I?
這裡是哪裡?
What happened since then?
在那之後發生了什麼事?
Am I dead?
難道我已經死了嗎?
Is this reality?
這是現實嗎?
Or is this hell?
還是地獄?
EPISODE 12 LIGHT IN THE DARKNESS
第 12 集 劇名:黑暗中的光芒
Visualize strongly now.
請妳用力想像
You will leave your body now.
妳將脫離身體
Your soul will be detached and enter Mr. Kudo's body.
變成只有靈魂的存在 進入久堂先生的體內
Once there, try to find his soul.
然後請在裡面找出他的靈魂
Yes.
知道了
Ms. Miyo... Please be safe.
美世小姐,請您一定要平安歸來
Miyo-chan, I know you can do it.
美世妹妹,妳一定辦得到
Ms. Miyo...
美世小姐...
Everyone here believes in you because we all care for you.
因為妳是我們重要的人 所以大家都很信任妳
Are you ready?
妳準備好了嗎?
Yes.
準備好了
I will surely return...
我一定會回來
with my husband-to-be.
而且是跟老爺一起回來
I’m ready to go.
我出發了
Sir...
老爺
This looks like...
這裡是...
The Saimori house...
齋森家
The Grotesqueries which were destroyed are now reappearing one by one.
本已殲滅的異形不斷冒出來
I was with Godo and the others, but now they’re gone...
直到剛才還在一起的 五道等人也消失無蹤
What is this place?
這個世界到底是哪?
It certainly isn't the mortal world.
果然不是現世嗎?
All I know is...
然而...
no matter where I am, I cannot die here.
不管這是哪裡,我都不能就這麼死去
Sir...
老爺
Miyo!
美世!
Miyo! Where are you?!
美世!妳在哪裡?
If you’re here, answer me!
如果妳在的話就回答我!
Miyo!
美世!
Where’s my husband-to-be?
老爺人在哪裡呢?
Who’s there?!
是誰在那邊?
Is anybody there?
有人在嗎?
Over here...
在這裡
Wait a minute!
等一下!
Why...?
為什麼...
Here... Over here...
在這裡,來這邊吧
W-Wait!
別走啊!
You are...
妳是...
Catch me if you can.
來這裡抓我吧
What... is this?
這是怎麼回事?
This way.
在這裡喔
I have to hurry and find my husband-to-be.
必須盡快趕到老爺身邊才行
This door...
這扇門...
I recognize it.
看起來很眼熟
Are you...
妳...
me...?
是我?
Miyo...
美世
I must go to her.
我要到美世身邊!
I was going to bring Miyo back.
我本來該去迎接美世
How pathetic am I...?
現在卻如此狼狽
I must see her once more... and apologize.
我得再見她一面,當面跟她道歉
But...
可是...
will I be able to?
我去得了嗎?
No, I have to!
不,我必須做到!
I can’t be trapped in a place like this.
我不能被困在這樣的地方
I can't die yet!
絕不能在這種地方喪命!
What are you doing here...?
妳究竟在這裡做什麼?
You won't see him.
妳無法見到老爺
Why?
為什麼?
You are not... good enough for him.
妳配不上老爺
You’re going to be alone.
妳一直都是孤單一人
Forever.
今後也是
Because it’s easier for you.
因為那樣比較輕鬆
That’s how you’ve been living until now.
妳一路上都是這麼活過來的
You know it in your heart, right?
其實妳自己也心知肚明吧?
He gave you so much kindness.
老爺對妳釋出善意
You flatly refused it
妳卻不屑一顧
and hurt him.
甚至傷害了老爺
Because of you, he is now wandering on the brink of death.
這都是妳的錯 害老爺如今在死亡深淵徘徊
Everyone who comes across you...
只要跟妳扯上關係
meets misfortune.
大家都會變得不幸
That’s why...
所以...
you shouldn’t be beside him.
妳不應該待在老爺的身邊
That may be true.
或許真是如此
I’m a failure in many ways.
我總認為自己很沒用
I’ve been wanting to change and stop seeing myself as a failure.
總是想改變只會消極思考的自己
As you said, I’m not good enough to be with him.
正如妳所說的 我的確不該待在老爺的身邊
I thought so, too.
我也一直都是那麼認為
But...
可是...
I don’t anymore.
現在不同了
Since you achieved a supernatural ability?
因為妳得到異能了嗎?
That doesn’t matter.
這與異能無關
Thanks to those around me who care for me,
多虧那些關心我的珍視之人
I now feel that it’s all right for me to be beside him.
我才覺得自己有資格陪伴在老爺身旁
Don’t lie.
妳不要說謊
You yourself think that it’s easier
妳一直認為孤身一人
to stay all alone.
比較輕鬆
No. That’s not true.
不對,沒那回事
Don’t lie!
少騙人了!
After Mother died, every day was a living hell.
自從母親大人死後 妳就過著地獄般的痛苦日子
So before long,
所以在不知不覺間
you made your heart go numb so you wouldn't feel anything.
為了感覺不到痛楚 妳讓自己的心變得麻木
There was no other way.
妳別無選擇
That was the only way to live.
唯有那麼做才能活下去
I thought that was my life... to be living that way.
我直到不久前還認為 自己的人生就只能那麼活下去
But... I believe I can change.
然而我現在深信可以改變自己
It’s too late to change!
事到如今已經改變不了了!
You’ve always given up on every little thing, haven't you?
妳往往都習慣放棄一切不是嗎?
But... I decided not to give up anymore!
不過我已經決定不再放棄了!
It’s impossible!
不可能!
It’s not impossible!
沒有不可能!
It is impossible!
那是不可能的!
Giving up is easy,
畢竟放棄更簡單
and you won’t get hurt!
也不會受到傷害!
That’s who you are.
妳就是那種人
You hurt his feelings
為了不讓自己遭受傷害
so that you wouldn’t get hurt!
於是就去傷害老爺!
So that’s why I have to apologize to him.
所以我必須向他好好道歉
My husband-to-be was always on my side.
老爺無時無刻總是站在我這邊
Although he believed in me,
他對我是百般信賴
I couldn’t believe in myself.
我卻沒勇氣相信自己
I was scared to get hurt.
我害怕受傷害
It’s all my fault.
是我不好
Don’t come near me!
別過來!
The possibility of getting hurt is scary...
雖然我仍怕受傷
but I won’t run away anymore.
但我不會再逃避了
I believe in my husband-to-be.
我願意相信老爺
And because he believes in me,
然後我決定要一併相信
I'll believe in myself too.
老爺所信任的自己!
I...
我...
I want to be beside him!
想待在老爺身邊!
I’m going to find him and bring him back
我要去迎接老爺了
so that I can live a happy life with him.
為了今後能跟他一起過上幸福的生活
I hope... you can.
要是真的能獲得幸福就好了
It’s his kumihimo cord.
這是老爺的髮繩
Sir!
老爺!
Miyo...?
美世?
Stand back!
請你退後!
What is this...?
這是怎麼回事?
Sir.
老爺
I've come to take you home.
我來接你回去了
Miyo...
美世
Sir!
老爺!
You're badly injured...
好嚴重的傷口
Don’t worry.
別擔心
It's just a scratch.
這點傷口完全不要緊
More importantly...
比起這個...
You.
你們幾個
Your Majesty!
陛下!
What is the situation?
情況如何?
Your Majesty.
向您報告
A girl who seems to be part of the Usuba family has appeared.
疑似是薄刃家的女孩現身了
Damned Usuba...
可惡的薄刃
Your Majesty, please rest your body.
陛下,請您好好休息吧
It's our highest priority now to eliminate
現在的首要之務
the Kudo family which poses a threat to us as well as the power of Dream-Sight.
是消除威脅到我們的 久堂家以及夢見之力
Miyo.
美世
Sir.
老爺
Please take my hand.
可以握住我的手嗎?
Your hand?
握妳的手?
Would you please...
能夠請你...
believe in me?
相信我嗎?
Of course.
當然可以
Let’s go home... together!
我們一起回去吧!
Yes.
好
Perish!
就這麼逝去吧!
Kiyoka Kudo!
久堂清霞!
Miyo Saimori!
齋森美世!
Miyo! It's coming!
美世!要來了!
You pesky little rats!
你們這群礙眼的鼠輩!
Be gone!
消失吧!
Where are we?
這裡是哪?
Miyo...
美世
Although it was my job to protect you,
本該是我保護妳
you saved me instead.
結果反倒被妳保護了
Sir, this...
老爺,你看這個
This kumihimo cord
是這條髮繩
guided me to where you were.
將我引導至老爺的身邊
Oh, so that's how...
原來如此,是那樣啊
I thought I had lost it in the battle.
我還以為髮繩在戰鬥中遺失了
I’ll tie it for you.
我幫你重新綁上
Can you crouch down, sir?
可以請你彎下身子嗎?
Yes, thank you.
好,麻煩妳了
There, it’s done.
綁好了
Thank you.
謝謝
Um, sir?
那個,老爺...
Hmm?
嗯?
At the Usuba house, I was asked what I wanted to do,
在薄刃家,當我被問到打算怎麼做時
and I answered, “I don’t know.”
當時是回答“我不知道”
Do you remember?
這件事你還記得嗎?
Yes.
記得
It was a lie when I said I didn’t know.
我說的那句“不知道”是騙人的
I’m sorry.
對不起
No.
不
I’m the one who should apologize.
我才要跟妳道歉
Pardon?
什麼?
I didn’t mean to hurt you,
我絲毫沒有傷害妳的意思
but I lost my temper and I said something unreasonable.
但當下忍不住動怒,不講道理
I sincerely apologize.
真的很抱歉
It’s all right.
我完全不介意
I... want to be beside you, sir.
我想跟老爺在一起
Miyo.
美世
Please let me always be by your side.
請讓我永遠待在你身邊
That was always my intention.
我一直都是如此打算的
If you don’t mind someone like me, I want you to be by my side.
如果妳不嫌棄我的話 希望妳能待在我身邊
Yes.
好的
Of course.
當然好
Good.
太好了
I didn’t know what I'd do if you had said no.
我心想要是妳不願意該怎麼辦
I would never say no.
我絕對不會說出那種話的
Kiyoka?!
清霞?
Ms. Miyo!
美世小姐!
- Commander! - Mr. Kudo!
-隊長! -久堂先生!
-Miyo! -Commander!
-美世妹妹! -隊長!
-Kiyoka! -Miyo!
-清霞! -美世小姐!
Miyo!
美世!
Everyone...
大家...
Sir,
老爺
everyone is waiting.
大家都在等我們
Let’s go back together.
我們一起回去吧
Yes, let’s go.
好,我們走吧
- Commander! - Young Master!
-隊長! -少爺!
Miyo-chan!
美世妹妹!
Commander! Wake up!
拜託隊長快醒來啊!
- Miyo! - Commander!
-美世! -隊長!
Miyo-chan...
美世妹妹
I’m relieved...
太好了
Ms. Miyo...
美世小姐
Commander!
隊長!
Are we... back?
我們回來了嗎?
Yes.
是的
We were so worried about you!
你真是愛讓人操心!
Sorry... to have made you worry.
抱歉,害大家擔心了
Sir...
老爺
Goodness, don’t cry.
別哭了,真是的
Commander!
隊長!
I’m so glad you’re okay!
幸好你平安無事!
Hey, Godo!
喂,五道!
Don’t cling to me! It's stifling!
別靠過來,熱死了!
Arata!
新先生!
Um, are you returning home?
那個,你要回去了嗎?
My work here is done, it seems,
我的工作似乎已經結束了
so I’m excusing myself.
所以就此告辭了
I really don’t know what to say about all of this, but...
對於這次的事,真不知道該說什麼...
You don’t have to mention it.
不必謝我
I just did what I wanted to do.
我只是照自己的意願做事
But,
不過啊
I still can’t...
我果然還是
go back to the Usuba house with you.
沒辦法跟你一起回薄刃家
I’m sorry.
對不起
Don’t apologize for something like that.
請妳別為那種事情道歉
You are family to us.
因為妳是我們的家人啊
Arata Tsuruki...
鶴木新
I’m going to request a rematch someday.
總有一天我會再度向你挑戰
I won’t lose next time.
下次絕不會輸
Very well. I’ll be ready anytime.
好,我隨時奉陪
Until then...
那我就失陪了
What? That can’t be...
怎麼會?沒想到陛下竟然...
Mikado has already lost the ability of revelation.
天皇已經喪失天啟之力
The fear of not being able to see into the future
所以看不見未來的恐懼
has taken over Mikado.
才會支配天皇的心智
He committed a sin by opening the Grave and placing many people's lives in danger...
他解開奧津城的封印 讓眾多百姓置身於危險中
We will surely have to...
我們總有一天
make him atone for it someday.
必定會要他為此好好贖罪
It feels like we were away for such a long time.
感覺像是睽違許久回到家
It certainly does.
就是說啊
Welcome home, sir.
歡迎回來,老爺
Well, it’s good to be home, Miyo.
好,我回來了,美世
Thus, my everyday life regained tranquility.
就這樣,我的日常生活再次回歸平穩
The restless nights of nightmares became a thing of the past.
再也不會因為做惡夢而痛苦的我
And now, we are finally able to enjoy having meals together
跟老爺一起用餐
while having trivial conversations.
聊些無關緊要的瑣事
The time I am able to spend with my husband-to-be...
能夠與老爺共度相同時光的片刻
is what happiness means to me.
對我而言就是幸福
These days, I realize that even more strongly.
在這幾天我重新意識到了這一點
SEVERAL DAYS LATER
(幾天後)
Peaceful days flew by quickly.
平穩的時光稍縱即逝
And before I knew it,
回過神來便發現
the day I was to try out my skills learned from Ms. Hazuki
驗收與葉月女士特訓成果的日子
had come.
就此到來了
PARTY DAY! BREAK A LEG, MIYO!
(派對日! 美世妹妹加油!)
Miyo.
美世
Sir.
老爺
Thank you for waiting.
讓你久等了
Uh... uh-huh.
呃,喔
Um, sir?
請問一下,老爺
How do I look?
你覺得如何?
Oh, you look beautiful.
這個嘛,妳非常漂亮
Thank you very much.
謝謝讚美
You look dashing too, sir.
老爺也非常帥氣
What are you saying, all of a sudden?
妳別突然說那種話啦
I-I'm sorry.
不好意思
Shall we go?
那我們走吧
Yes.
好的
Miyo.
美世
I want to ask you again just to make sure since we're not in a dream right now.
在夢中以外的地方 我想再次確認妳的心意
I know how troublesome I can be.
妳願意跟如此麻煩的男人
But will you marry me?
結為連理嗎?
You're not troublesome at all.
老爺怎麼會是麻煩的男人
I'm much more trouble...
應該是我比較麻煩...
How about you?
我才想反問老爺呢
Won't you regret your decision?
你不後悔嗎?
There's no way I'll regret it.
我怎麼會後悔呢
I'm the one who chose you.
因為是我選擇了妳
I know I'm inexperienced,
雖然我還不夠成熟
but it will be an honor.
不過今後還請你多多關照
Likewise. It will be an honor.
我也一樣,要請妳多多指教
Subtitle translation by: Ikuko Ohno
字幕翻譯:黃琳雅